We are going to be discussing from pipelines to prompts
surviving the shift from to AI.
We have some fantastic speaker panelists
who have agreed to join us very late notice.
So please, as they come up.
Give them a massive round of applause because they didn't know
they were doing this till 11:00 last night.
So could I please ask Stephane Jourdan,
Pini Reznik and Simon
Rohrer to come up to the stage?
They're not going to use the steps.
Nobody's going to use the steps.
So hello,
I'm going to get you all to introduce yourselves a little.
Just give you a couple of minutes on who you are,
where you work and a bit of your background as well.
And then we can sort of kick off with the actual topic itself.
So, Simon, do you want to kick off?
Sure. Hi, I'm Simon. I work.
In Denmark and
and what is working and also.
Effectively to.
For so many used developers.
And I was not happy.
Which is a consultancy
helping us to to try
mostly around software development infrastructure
and actually building large laptops.
And in a second company, the first one was Container
Solutions, which was
great eventually and.
Delivered a lot of large platforms.
And I'm Stefan, I'm the CEO and co-founder, and
it's basically context for production agents or agents in production.
And for the past 15 years, I've built
different startups for managing production systems.
And the last one was acquired by Sage.
So I was building cloud there.
Okay, so I'm going to be looking at my phone
because like I said, this is a quite a late notice panel.
So people in this room have lived through more than one industry earthquake.
They've built the cloud and champion DevOps.
They've bolted security onto delivery pipelines with DevSecOps,
and now they're facing the next big move AI native development.
How's it going, fellas?
So I have there been any
major seismic shift in the in what you're doing now?
Who wants to take that first?
I think
so we started doing with support and it was awesome.
So it was in the beginning of the 1990s.
So at that point, it was
quite clear.
It was a statement that will change in characterization.
Yes, it is similar.
It's not just changing processes, which is changing everything.
And it is maybe
100 times more complicated than
the 12 was limited to the 50s.
So engineering is what do you see now?
Is that the moment we started using.
And very quickly they want to vertical.
Yeah.
And then we need to get out the to do something else.
And then we have to do something else.
Everyone has to develop a and I think this,
this is something that is for my career.
When the pieces of technology so quickly changing, so much different companies.
And with all those.
Other
roles in the room starting to bring things into the pipeline.
Is that having an effect that is rippling
across the DevOps space?
Absolutely.
I think it seems to be a bit behind
the general development.
I can guess why.
Just get the more we needed to make myself down here,
if you think that it's something that
the design fails,
what is needed, but I think
there was a bit more.
The velocity is a bit more afraid.
There's still.
But if it's not clear how the is going to affect,
you need to get into all of those products
or when you do that.
Stefan, we were talking earlier about you tend to look after things in production.
Do you want to pick that up? What that means?
Yeah.
What we observe now with agents
like creating PRS 24 hours a day.
Now we have, like, CEOs deploying stuff in production.
We have.
I love and faces for everybody on that.
I'm talking about microphones.
And now everybody's deploying
fixes, changes new features all the time.
And previously it was already like complicated
just to know what's the impact of of your change.
Not to mention just the things that drifted manually or for some reasons.
So now you have agents by everyone, from everyone doing things in production.
How do you know the impact of this 24 hours a day?
It's constant and you really need proactive agents and all the contexts.
What changed yesterday?
What was the relationship between this service and this other service?
How do you know that this service was actually connecting to the readings?
But the variable was not.
The name was the IP, that sort of stuff.
So it's not only about like root cause analysis.
It's really about like the, the context, all the knowledge you can have from prod
your multiple accounts that all the stuff and agents today
you mentioned like DevOps is a bit back in,
in, in the space because the floppies had a lot of tools, a lot of
data to work with the code, etc.
but for products we really need to to keep the lights up.
So yeah, that data and that context is your point
these days, including agents to fix this 24 hours a day.
Because even from a security perspective,
all the things that are being patched as well, constantly, you need to ensure
that the blast radius of things are still working after this.
So everything, everything is so is going so quickly these days.
We need to we need that data proactively.
Simon, I can see you're violently agreeing.
So I work at a regulated industry.
We can't quite move as fast, but we're still moving pretty fast. I,
like I said, I've been spearheading this and sort of coaching developers through.
And I think one of the things for me that surprised the developers or,
you know, we did you build your running.
So it is really developer operators.
The thing that has surprised
our developers the most is how useful the agents are for diagnosing production.
Yes, genuinely throw them at Elastic logs
plus ServiceNow incident reports, plus the code and the combination.
Like you said, is this knowledge that the agents can have
they will solve an issue in 30s
that could have taken developers hours
or maybe even days to fully understand this stuff is so powerful, you know,
and I think the people
who are just using it in the development context really should,
if they have that data available to them, like they say,
if they've got the good observability stack in place, should start to expand
there. They they use more broadly into this.
And I think, you know, we are living through a seismic shift.
We we don't know where we're going to end up.
We don't know what the earthquake will do to us because those
those tremors are still going and they're going to be going for a while.
But I think these things are fairly clear that production
use of the agents is just as important as.
You mentioned there about the observability stack.
It's one of the guardrails that we know we should have.
I know that everybody would like to have not everybody has,
but there are other guardrails we need to think about as well.
So what are the sort of like musts?
What are the ones that we should all go
if we haven't got that this is going to cause us problems.
Can I sure.
Quite depressing conversation
with a fairly a developer, fairly new to a gente coding last week.
We use OpenCode on top of
AI and he was saying, look, I don't need to do linting
because the code that comes out of the LM is perfect.
No. I then pointed him at the article
on Harness Engineering and her latest one on linting.
For me, that's that's the absolute O6 the agents.
Right.
Poor quality code.
They're great at writing code.
The loop you can get around and the productivity.
But ultimately the code quality is not awesome.
You need that combination of determinism again, as has been written about that at length,
the combination of determinism for code quality and the feedback loop
to be able to do that.
So for me, number one really is linting.
You know, you can add more and more more.
You can write custom linter as you can use tools like
Adam Torn Hills Code Health to go much deeper
into the quality of the code the agent is written.
But basically get get your linting turned up to 11.
That would be my major tip.
The one thing that is pretty clear
is that you cannot continue to use
humans for every code review things like this.
Yes, none of it is. None of it is practical.
Like in the beginning, of course,
that's that's a way to ensure quality at a certain extent.
But that creates all kind of problems.
If you have you have to have senior engineers who understand code.
They have to maintain their capability to understand code, which is actually hard.
If you don't write the code, it's they become bottleneck, right?
So if if code development goes so much faster,
humans cannot keep up with reviewing the code.
That's why Harness Engineering and all kind of like swarms of specialized agents
and stuff that they're doing this, it's absolutely essential.
Otherwise the productivity of single developer may go up,
but of the team remains relatively stable.
Yeah.
And what I observe in in such teams, it's also that now
new services are becoming like unknown to the to the rest of the team
because it's been deployed by someone who created this by an agent
because like Claude decided
that this was a good idea to create this new microservice,
and it's deployed and nobody knows really how it works.
Like why it connects.
Are you mentioned like the logs and elastic or something?
Why elastic in this case? Just because code decided it.
So you need to have that knowledge somewhere because maybe
maybe another service was used previously for this other system.
So you kind of have like God rails
to ensure that those sort of things don't happen.
But it's not what I observe.
I observed really like a lot of heterogeneous
environments being more and more deployed.
And that's why you need like
even more information to debug it, because no one knows really these days.
What are what's actually deployed.
And the information that
you're getting is often like it has to be presented
in the way that humans can understand it, make the tradeoff decisions.
It's not often the case. It's often
there's mountain of information, and you need to go one by one.
That is not practical for human to do the same like that.
So that has to be entirely new tools
developed that will show people the trade offs. Right?
That's where people need to be involved more.
Not not in reviewing every line of code.
That's probably not important.
But but the trade of decisions, cost versus
speed, architectural decisions
which kind of to which observability tool to connect
those are absolutely has to be done by by humans.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'm interested in a sort of
well while I do get the
we will have to get to a point where humans can't review the code.
I do remember what guy was talking about this morning, that if you lose
that context of what the code is doing, that's also problematic as well.
So I would be talking here that we're going to have to have some,
some way of reliably skimming what we've got so that we can
then I know we can already get documentation,
we can already get system diagrams, we can already get an awful lot
by pointing an LM at the code.
And to tell me what it's doing
is that what we need to invest in, in some things that are allowing us
to get even better views on that code that's going in.
Generally explainability of the code of the systems
so humans can understand, make decisions.
I don't think it's at this point is going far enough.
Yeah.
We really need next level of tooling.
Like if we if we assume that AI is sort of next level
of abstraction, then we need to move away from reviewing code and move to that
next level of abstraction to new language that describes the system.
I don't think that exists. Right.
So and that's why we are forced into going and reviewing every, every line of code,
every every line of operational logs and stuff.
This is not practical.
Like this is like going into assembly and reviewing every line of code.
I agree.
This again, this will become another sound like a broken record on this.
And we're in the middle of the change here.
Simon Wardley in Chicago have written written quite a bit about this,
about how the explainability of the code and being able to understand the code
rather than write it is the is the new skill.
But again, I don't think the tools are there.
Judas worked a lot, some development and glamorous toolkit is pretty impressive
for sort of single codebases.
But when you get to enterprise scale, there is.
Nothing. Nothing there right now.
And you can't just rely on the LLM because the LLM will hallucinate.
It will miss stuff.
You need something deterministic to tell you what your code is doing,
and it's going to be very interesting.
And something close to the
observer as well is teams taking on much more production systems
or applications to maintain that they don't know about,
like it was inherited by, I don't know, another team that left or an acquisition
something like this.
And now it becomes it becomes it's it's not possible with the right tools
to just manage this in prod, because if you have that context,
if you have like you can you can do this in like seconds
now, which was just not so doable at all, only only a year ago.
So that changed a lot.
Like those teams are taking over a lot more than previously.
That's yeah, it's something that I've seen as well.
And it is.
But you still have the problem that you have to guide the model quite
strictly as you're going through these systems, because it will hallucinate
if you if you just give it free rein to tell me what this is doing,
it will it'll tell you what you want to hear.
Then we get context.
That's why you need the proper context of the company.
Like this.
Information is crucial to to to to handle it correctly.
Yeah.
There is this element of like
we compare tend
to compare systems to perfection.
Right.
Like it hallucinates.
And that's a problem because we expect it to be perfect.
I'm like okay, but humans are perfect.
They're not perfect.
I mean, we all pollution it in a way, right?
And we all do stupid things.
So we need to compare it.
It's like self-driving car, right?
It's not about zero accidents.
It's about less accidents that what we have as humans. So,
this there always will be problems,
but that's okay as long as we can manage them.
So let's actually lean into some of those problems.
We've all read a few of the really good, terrible things
the railway GCP outage last week and AWS loss of DNS.
So there's been some really
thorny issues.
Is there
anything that we need to be doing
to make sure we're not falling into the same sort of traps?
And is there anything that we need
to be starting to think about as part of our pipelines
that that would help prevent this sort of errors?
I'm being very polite when I say errors.
I think it is.
And again, this is where the what we should have been doing as humans,
literally anything goes wrong.
And I think this is is it mature?
Hashimoto's Harness Engineering, anything that goes wrong,
feed it back into the harness and then never let that class of error
happen again.
Do something deterministic in your harness if you can,
to make sure that class of never never happens again.
Feedback, feedback feedback.
Which is the same as you would do in a team, which is.
Exactly.
How exactly this a high functioning team should be doing.
That class should be doing that type of thing anyway.
Yeah,
it's just pins up whatever you already have.
If you have a good system that doesn't fail,
then then you go faster without failing much, right?
If you have terrible system,
it's terrible faster.
Yeah. That's it. It's what?
The report last year. Exactly, exactly.
Yeah, yeah.
And similarly what what what we observe is self-learning agents for for production.
So like it fixed an issue.
It used Century or Datadog or whatever like an information.
And we have like reflectors agents like learn from
both the problem and the solution and it gets added to the memory as well.
So it's like a self, yes
reflecting agent with a very specific memory.
And it learns what happened over time as well.
That's a new class of of agents for prod.
That's very exciting because it really learned something
very specific to the company.
And it's it can be really tailored.
That's we that's what we observe as well with more enterprise
see companies that have like huge no human can really know
what's really happening on such large deployments.
But conceptually speaking, it's similar to a good healthy team
during continuous integration anyway. Right?
There are teams that are running builds.
Whatever you have red building, they do nothing about it.
Right.
And you can actively fix the same like and now agents are doing it.
But conceptually it's the same thing.
Like do you have a discipline to continuously improve?
If yes, then you can can build the agents that are doing it.
Yeah. Right.
But but if many companies, they don't have the discipline
and they are just doing it as sort of settlements,
then everything becomes much worse.
They're going to fail faster.
Yes, yes.
And and that's the thing that
the slow
speed of human was sort of hiding those problems.
But the most advanced themes, they, they explicitly
like lowered the water to expose the, the underwater stones and then fix them.
So the other side of this, this coin, I suppose,
is that if we do get everybody to a point where they are,
they're lowering the water, they're looking at their
they're looking at all those bad things.
Do we get to a point where we can end the on core rotors
and PagerDuty?
Well, I'm building such a product.
So that's what. I'd say. So I'm biased.
But yeah obviously you can plug such an agent to to your PagerDuty alerts.
And then it at least it can start investigating for you.
It's free.
Am you get paid by the time you get out of bed.
At least you can have like an agent, like giving you a markdown
file with the right information, the right logs, the right.
That's sort of information that the private
the internal information from the company.
So yes, that's what we do.
It starts to exist, it's working.
And I hope everyone gets something like this not to be woken up at 3 a.m.
again.
So you at least end up with something like fourth line support.
So effectively the agent becomes third line and worst case there's an
attached to go. To do. Yeah,
yeah.
We start to observe this as well for triage.
So like first the first responders when an issue or customer issue
gets routed, the wrong team for example
like agents with the right context, the internal context of the company,
it can help here as well for agents so that it
helps here as well.
Nothing to it.
It sounds like a dream.
Yeah, it's obviously a self-healing system.
That would be the total dream.
But I think the reality of it is I don't see our jobs going away anytime soon.
They just will morph into something slightly different.
Okay, I'm going to ask us one more question,
and then I might see if there's anything from the audience, if that's okay.
So imagine we're here in a two years time
and same panel, same group.
What is it that what's the piece of information
that you've shared today that you think you'll look back and go,
oh God, that was completely wrong.
I don't know.
What I said, I. Really I've stumped them.
I would probably be more optimistic than you on the LM output quality.
Things are going so fast and pretty sure
in two years from now we'll have
amazing models.
And yeah, probably two years from now I would regret to to to say
the same thing than you, that they are pretty dumb at the moment because.
Yeah, but maybe, maybe agents won't be a thing serious from now.
I don't know why.
Why would we need agents if we have different systems that deploy,
I don't know, build and deploy?
I'll probably answer a different question.
Yeah. No problem.
But I think there's this,
I think naive way of looking at it that the first,
the easiest way to look into AI is to say whatever we're doing now can be automated
and done and fraction of the time in 10% of the time and 1% of the time.
So the naive way is to say we will have
just 10% of the developers, and the rest can go home and forget about it.
That sounds pretty stupid.
Again, it's I think there's Germans paradox.
There is clearly when something becomes cheaper than we do a lot more of that.
I think the direction is that
the software development is something that is going to explore.
Everyone is going to build software.
I don't think they have the tooling for that yet.
What we call white coding, it has to be sort of built on top of bigger platforms
that they provide the large scale functionality,
but everyone will build their own front end,
their own last mile of consumption. Right?
So there will be sort of explosion of small
software on the on the last mile, and there will be
massively bigger systems that we could never build without AI.
Yeah, right.
And that will be built by professionals or for developers, not by white coders.
Yeah. Agree.
I would agree with you on that.
I think software development as a profession is going nowhere.
I'm still answering your question.
I have no crystal ball.
I literally I cannot see into the future, but I agree,
I think developments going nowhere.
There's the one thing I have learned more and more as I do this is I
develop skills, skill engineering and software engineering.
Especially when you get into sophisticated skills.
Software engineering is going nowhere as a profession.
The talk and for me, and I'm prepared to take the other side of the bet on LMS,
I genuinely am.
I think Polluter Nation is how they work.
I don't think the hallucination problem is going to go away ever.
But don't because I think it's inherent until we get a new class of model.
But I think that's fine.
I think that's absolutely fine.
I think software developers plus LMS are incredibly powerful,
and for me, that's that's the main learning I have had, is that it
is it's the two things working together that really, really give the power.
I don't think there's going to be many citizens, developers, like you said,
for the for the sort of real business logic, for anything
sophisticated, it is always going to be a software engineering mindset.
I have lived, I'm old enough to have lived through, well,
I didn't live through coal.
I wasn't quite there, but COBOL was meant to take away, suffered
a sequel was meant to take away software development for GLS.
We're going to take it away. Suffer.
It doesn't happen.
This is no different.
I never is a very long time, right.
But it's definitely not going away in
for Sable future current toolsets currently LMS, current ways of building.
And even if we look 1 or 2 years forward,
it's not going to like the.
It's clear that citizen developers, they can only go so far.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
And full disclosure, that last question was the only one I used
that Claude came.
Okay.
I said, I'd say we've probably got time
for a couple of questions from the audience.
Yeah, I'll.
We've got a microphone coming your way.
So if you could just hang on a set.
Thank you.
This is Prince.
Prince is helping us today.
Everyone give Prince a quick round of applause.
Thank you.
Thank you. Thanks for the great discussion.
You really enjoyed it.
I just wanted to put on my contrarian hat
and maybe share maybe a slightly unpopular view.
But I was listening to Bloomberg this morning
and they were saying like a bunch of, like massive companies,
like just got all canceled their cloud code line sensors,
including like Uber and Microsoft.
And yeah, a lot of the kind of things that we were talking about there, like
if you like, went to the Dev Conference five years ago and you said, you know,
you're not going to have any idea what's going on,
you know, lots of control, lots of other standing, you know, like,
like random choices, like on, like spinning up data stories,
like, just sounds like total chaos.
Do you think, like, this is really the way engineering is going to go,
like in the future or like the value is really there or we're kind of,
you know, it's going to be some implosion in the next, next couple of years.
And I'll just like preface that, like if you go back like ten years ago,
it feels very much like self-driving cars, you know, like 2014.
We're all like, wow, self-driving cars, like six months.
They're going to be here.
You can drive to the airport and back, you know, it's perfect.
But then all the edge cases and so on meant that, you know,
there's still probably more taxi drivers in London today than it was back then.
And all of us have driving car systems that are that are working today, sort of.
They all have like humans, you know, kind of remoting into to kind of
make sure that they don't get confused because,
you know, they can only kind of work like 80% of the time.
Do you not think the same is with software?
And then we're not going to have anything like reliable or maintainable or
sane to work with.
Not really a question, but just
a comment from the question. No, it was a bit of.
A question.
I will take that briefly.
I Microsoft.
Start Claude Code because they.
Don't get money from it. They they. Are.
Radically pushing their engineers to use GitHub Copilot.
They're also rebranding rebranding Claude coworker as Microsoft Copilot.
So it's a bit of a weird one with that Microsoft News story, Microsoft
are still pushing their employees to use AI all the time.
24 over seven the Uber one I don't think they've actually got.
I think they've just they just ended up.
But spending all of their AI budget in four months
rather than 12.
Like I was saying.
I mean, for me, absolutely, there is no self-driving.
Self-Driving cars. Yes. Agree.
And that's what I was saying about self-driving agents
building all the software.
It's not it's co-driver, very much co-driver, but
I think the quality is there.
You know, again, I am hands on as after 30 years in the industry,
I'm still building hands on software and the productivity gains are huge.
The quality is there.
If you do Harness Engineering, if you do not do good
Harness Engineering, the quality is terrible.
If you spend about as much time engineering your harness as you do
on prompting the actual functional output, you will get really good quality stuff.
You genuinely will.
So I disagree that this is sort of fashion.
The pan.
I think this is absolutely is the way for
okay.
Thank you, thank you.
Got one more.
I think I've got time for one more.
I think. Yeah.
Okay. Yes.
Oh well. That's too high. Yeah.
So in a way, I guess what you all been talking about,
like, things get sped up, like, there is a lot more stuff, right?
Than I think.
When any team starts becoming more successful, like,
the most cars resource becomes the human brain like.
And what do you do in your companies to, like,
you know, guide the cognitive resources of your organizations on the right stuff?
It can be like what peer reviews to review, what page called
should actually reach a human, when should it do that, etc..
It's like.
It's a very big topic, right?
It's because
what we see is that
generally there is the cognitive.
It's it goes both ways.
One, you need to leverage human brain, but the second you need to protect it,
because there is a lot of like the nature of work with
AI is very different because normally you would think a bit
and then you would spend like two days coding,
which is pretty relaxing exercise, right?
It's not very demanding.
Now you are thinking very hard.
Then ten minutes and goes away, comes back and then you need to think again, right.
So this this leads to a lot of stress and cognitive load
and people are really burning out if it's not managed correctly.
Right.
On the other side you have a single person can generate massive amount of code
and there is no often there is no need for a team, right?
But but without a team, you don't have sort of back and forth between humans.
So I don't have a clear answer for that.
But it's a really big topic.
I think the work environment for developers will change dramatically.
Right.
And we need to to address this very explicitly
with no answers, no, no clear answers, because people like
one of our customers said they actually every few weeks
they need to send a person for a week home just to relax.
Because just to decompress.
Well, there goes so fast, but they're there to blow.
This is amazing.
After a month of working like that just cannot continue.
Yeah, I think there is pressure from some quarters
to actually have multiple agents running in on multiple tasks.
Yeah. And yeah, wonderful.
That sounds great.
But it will just destroy people's minds very, very quickly.
The context.
Yeah. It was context
switching working late hours because you want to see what they did.
And commits are coming now 10 p.m.
and 11.
It's. Yeah.
And you cannot stop because like I want to see the result.
And so this is this is the sort of slot machine,
the variable reward which the Jagers talked about.
It is it's addictive.
It is because.
You're talking about isn't it.
I'm afraid I have to wind us up.
I've been given the t signals.
So thank you very much.
To the panel, to Simon, to Pini and to Stefan.
Thank you very much. Thank you, thank you.